# Leonard [Leo] Esere

21630 Milsa Dr San Antonio Leonardesere@gmail.com | Call:210.441.8307

## **EDUCATION**

University of Texas at San Antonio BS Economics | Management of Technology Graduate Student Certification

CompTIA Cloud+, CompTIA Security+, AWS SysOpps |Solutions Arti | UTSA 6 Months Full Stack Web Dev

## **Summary:**

Five combined years in HelpDesk, Network Admin, EndUser Security, and IT\_Specialist(Storage and Cloud)

Experience in standing up and maintaining servers in a cloud environment (AWS)

Web Programmer: HTMLv5, CSS framework, SQL, JavaScript, Powershell, Node.js, JQuery, JSON,

AJAX, APIs, GitHub, GitLab, online information sourcing using google and other search resource.

Strong background in Active Directory design and support. IIS, BootLocker, AirWatch, VSphere, RDP, CA, Skype.

Strong background in designing, maintaining, and managing VMWare virtual server environments,

Strong background in Office 365 implementation and support, (SasS), IBM Communication.

Strong working knowledge of networking technologies.

Strong background in Linux system implementation and administration skills

Entry level background in Single Sign on and Two Factor Authentication technology; Okta, RSA

Experience in the design and implementation of Identification and Authentication Management solutions; Okta

Strong working knowledge of SNOW, Salesforce, and Remedy.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### MEDTRONIC INC

Junior Network Administrator San Antonio, Texas

October 2018 – January 2020

- Managing Microsoft Identity Management products (Active Directory, Active Directory Federation Services, and Office 365) serving as an enterprise-wide directory containing 21k Objects
- Creating and managing application integrations for identify and access management. Having Experience of Creating conditional Access policies **Multifactor authentication** (**MFA**), Resetting MFA and Resolving the MFA issues.
- Creating and maintaining **User accounts, Profiles, Security, rights, disk space** and process monitoring using Active Directory.
- Familiarity in the following areas: **single sign-on, enterprise directory** architecture and design, directory schema, namespace, replication topology, resource provisioning, role-based access Control, user lifecycle.
- Strong hands-on administration experience on Windows 2012 server **Forest, Domain trust, AD,** DFS, **DNS, WINS, DHCP, Group Policy, Distribution lists,** Windows folder security, and IP filter.
- Resolving hardware/Operating Systems and application software issues within SLA
- Manage user citrix virtual environment hypervisor/
- Configure user SSTP using Palo Alto Networks (GlobalProtect)
- **Endpoint** security experience (for customer remote access)
- Experience using Wireshark/TCP Dump to analyse network packets

- Used SIEM (McAfee ESM), and SolarWinds Threat Monitor to monitor, identify and the forward to teir3 if needed for further investigation
- Lead **on-boarding and handling users, client machines,** and all infrastructure including servers, workstations, routers etc.
- Install new / rebuild existing servers and **configure**, **services**, **settings**, **directories**, storage, etc. in accordance with standards and project/operational requirements.
- Providing remote and hands-on administration of **Various hardware** and desktop applications
- Experience on **LAN Cabling, RJ 45 crimping, Labelling,** Patch Panel, PC Junction boxes, Phone Switches and Rack set-up.
- Creating templates from VM's and deploying VM's from templates and allocate resources.

## PRO-VIGIL SURVEILLANCE

IT SPECIALIST San Antonio, Texas August2017 – July 2018

- Troubleshoot Network equipment, IP and analogy camera installation, Support Field Technicians over the phone
- IP conflicts issues troubleshooting, DHCP server problem IP subnetting and assignments
- New user account creation and assignment, New employee account setup and creation in AD
- Remote Desktop support with TeamViewer
- Net-suite setup FireEye account creation WatchGuard Firewall Monitor and configuration User account management,
- Adding Users to Salesforce servers managing/monitoring my company AWS Immix servers,
- Perform security training to Pro-Vigil internal employees and clients.
- Configuration of Synology NAS, setting up CSM, Virtual Machines on Synology NAS
- Doing Port forwarding rules on the customer Routers, IP Whitelisting, and MAC Pass-through.
- Setting up Access Points and Clients Bridges (Engenius). Defining best configuration for devices.
- Completely setting up a Network with Pro-Vigil Device.
- Server room Network Equipment racking and stacking of Network equipment.
- Cable Run to new workstation(s).
- Extensive Knowledge of Synology NAS \*Engenius APs and CBs \*CradlePoints Routers Ubiquity Switches Trednet Switches
- Do Field service for escalations and hot sites. Manages all local computers and Network

## **INTERFACE SECURITY SYSTEM** Plano, Texas

Help Desk Support II

Sep, 2015 – Aug, 2017

- Monitor camera systems remotely configure customer camera/DVRs, and alarm Panels. Answering incoming calls, and providing Technical Support for field technicians
- Provides responses to tickets in a timely manner.
- Assists with basic troubleshooting, backup, and archiving.
- Establishes priorities on Help Desk tickets based on established helpdesk and departmental guidelines and procedures.